# **Matthew Gouvin**

A software engineer who uses modern technologies to design, build and test software and web applications; interested in machine learning and data visualization. Searching for an internship in software engineering to gain hands-on experience with emerging technologies and to develop mentorships with experienced engineers.

#### **Education**

#### THE GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY

B.S. Computer Science. GPA 3.98.

Washington, D.C.

Aug. 2020 - May 2024

Relevant Coursework: Software Engineering, Database Systems, Data Structures & Algorithms.

Awards: Dean's List 2020-2022

#### CHARIHO HIGH SCHOOL

**Software Development Intern** 

Wood River Junction, RI

Aug. 2016 – June 2020

National Honor Society. Editor-in-Chief of school newspaper. President of the Chariho High School Chorus.

### **Experience**

#### SURVICE ENGINEERING COMPANY

Graduated as valedictorian with high honors.

Belcamp, MD

May 2022 — Present

- Developed a web application that provides data management and research support for Department of Defense and federal government users.
- Designed, implemented, and tested advanced features that improve data analysis capabilities.
- Utilized MySQL, Express, NodeJs, and Angular to respectively make database schema changes, create RESTful API endpoints, engineer useful API services, and build components on the user interface.
- Refactored existing software modules to optimize performance and enhance the overall software design.
- Collaborated with team members, reviewed code, and worked in an agile development environment.

#### USABLE SECURITY AND PRIVACY LAB

Washington, D.C.

#### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

March 2022 — May 2022

- Examined the security differences between applications on the Google Play store and applications on various third-party APK application stores over time.
- Utilized web scraping tools that collect data from third-party APK application stores.
- Designed a relational database schema that stores APK application data collected from web-scraping tools.
- Participated in weekly reading groups, discussion groups and scrum meetings.

# THE WESTERLY SUN

Westerly, RI

#### **Contributing Writer**

July 2019 — June 2021

- Authored over 35 stories for southwestern Rhode Island communities.
- Developed a specialized focus on education, local elections, and municipal government.
- Interviewed local leaders and community members in addition to examining government documents.

### **Projects**

#### UNIVERSITY MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

Co-Creator Spring 2022

- Created a responsive web application that manages college applications, class registration, and academic advising.
- Designed the relational database schema, implemented it with Amazon Web Services, and utilized the database in the management of personnel and course information.
- Developed the system following an Agile development methodology.

## **Technical Skills**

Programming: Java, C, Python, JavaScript (Node.js), Typescript (Angular), SQL (MySQL, SQLite), HTML, CSS, R.

Operating Systems: Windows, MAC OS, Linux. Web Design: Designed www.mattgouvin.me